Guide to the Logan Family Papers, 1952-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Logan Family papers 1952-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Logan family
2.7 Linear Feet 2025 Items
The Logan family were Southern Baptist missionaries to Nigeria from 1952 to 1982. Wayne Logan was a dentist practicing in Enugu and Ibadan. In the late 1970s, the family moved to Lagos, where Dr. Logan taught orthodontics at the University of Lagos Dental School.
The Logan Family Papers includes many slides documenting the Logan family's life in Nigeria, including missionaries, missionary children, churches, and local Nigerian culture. Also includes books from their library collection.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Logan Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013.
Biographical Note
The Logan family were Southern Baptist missionaries to Nigeria from 1952 to 1982, working on behalf of the Southern Baptist Convention's Foreign Mission Board. Wayne Logan was a dentist and worked in the Baptist Dental Centre in Ibadan. After 1960 the family moved to Enugu, where they established a Dental Clinic. In the late 1970s the family moved again to Lagos, where Dr. Logan taught Orthodontics at the University of Lagos Dental School.
Collection Overview
The Logan Family Papers collection is divided into two series: Visual Materials and Printed Materials. The visual materials consist mostly of slides. Many of the slides document the Logan family's life in Nigeria and in America, from the children's birth to late teens. Others document village life, peoples, patients, markets, church-life, baptisms, weddings, amongst others. The printed materials include several books from the Logan family's collection that document African culture, history and customs.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Logan, William Wayne
Logan family
Southern Baptist Convention
Southern Baptist Convention. Foreign Mission Board
Baptists -- Missions -- Nigeria
Nigeria -- History -- 20th century
Married people in missionary work -- Africa
Children of missionaries -- Africa
Dentistry -- Nigeria
Contents of Collection
- Visual Materials, 1952-1982, (4 boxes)
  The Visual Materials Series documents the Logan family's life in America and in Nigeria. The series also depicts life in Africa--customs, village-life, people, Lagos, teeth, patients, markets amongst others. Many of the trays had accompanying notes, which have been included at the beginning of their respective slides. Arranged in chronological order.
  - Tray #1, 1952 to 1953, Wiggins to Ibadan (Box 1)
  - Tray #2, 1953-1955, family in Nigeria (Box 1)
  - Tray #3, 1954-1955, family (Box 1)
  - Tray #4, 1956-1958, family (Box 1)
  - Tray #5, 1957-1960, family in Nigeria and America (Box 1)
  - Tray #6, 1960-1962, family in Nigeria and America (Box 1)
  - Tray #7, 1961-1963, family in Nigeria and America (Box 1)
  - Tray #9, 1967-1969, family in Nigeria and America (Box 1)
  - 1952-1970, America and Nigeria, with a few family (Box 2)
  - 1953-1955, Nigeria (Box 2)
  - 1968-1970, Nigeria, family (Box 2)
  - 1969-1971, Nigeria, family (Box 2)
  - 1971-1973, family (Box 2)
  - 1971-1975, Nigeria (Box 2)
  - 1979-1980, Nigeria (Box 2)
  - 1980-1981, Nigeria (Box 2)
  - 1955-1978, Nigeria, a few family (Box 3)
  - 1958-1973, Nigeria (Box 3)
  - 1958-1981, Nigeria (Box 3)
  - 1959-1974, family (Box 3)
  - 1953-1977, Nigeria (Box 3)
  - 1961-1981, Nigeria (Box 3)
  - 1958-1979, Nigeria (Box 3)
  - 1969-1982, America, family (Box 4)
  - Teeth, Nigeria (Box 4)
  - Undated, family (Box 4)
  - Undated, Africa (Box 4)
  - Baptist Missions Abroad, Baptist Foreign Mission Board, film strip with no audio (Box 3)
- Printed Materials, 1959-1994, (2 boxes)
  The Printed Materials Series contains books from the Logan's library, pertaining to Nigerian history, culture and language. The items are arranged in alphabetical order by author.
  - Aluko, T. M., One Man, One Wife, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Susan, May Perry of Africa, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Akande, S. T., Speaking in Tongues Yesterday and Today, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Browne, Stanley, Medicine and Faith in a Primitive Community, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Burks, Edgar, Planting the Redeemer's Standard, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Cansdale, G. S., West African Snakes, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Cowley, William, Mission: Nigeria, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Davidson, Basil, The Growth of African Civilization, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Delano, Isaac, Yoruba Proverbs, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Fletcher, Jesse, Wimpy Harper of Africa, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Fuller, Aletha, More Than a Memory, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Fuller, John, Fever!, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Obe, Peter, Nigeria, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Ogbalu, F. C., Ibo-English Phrase Book, undated (Box 5)
  - Patterson, I. N., Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow, 1964, (2 copies) (Box 5)
  - Ross, Emory and Myrta, Africa Disturbed, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Segun, Mabel, Friends, Nigerians, Countrymen, 1977, (2 copies) (Box 6)
  - Syme, Ronald, Nigerian Pioneer, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Thorp, Ellen, Ladder of Bones, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Wall, Martha, Splinters from an African Log, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Webster, J. B. The Growth of African Civilization: The Revolutionary Years, West Africa since 1800, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Whirley, Carlton, A Story to Tell, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Crisis '66, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Ibadan Chopping Guide, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Nigerian Heritage, undated (Box 6)